# **SEAN HEGARTY**

Freelance Senior Integrated Artworker 07855 456521 sean.hegarty@btinternet.com

I've spent the past 20 years helping clients build strong, clear and consistent visual communications. My work displays a proven track record of inventive and compelling creative work across print and digital mediums.

Developed knowledge of creating HMTL hand coded web banners (Greensock) and produced 2D social media animations using After Effects.

## **KEY ATTRIBUTES AND KNOWLEDGE**

- > Craft and prepare artwork including press, POS, OOH, bespoke print, digital OOH, online banners and email in strict adherence to client guidelines. View my work at hegartycreative.com
- > Tailor existing artwork to suit diverse applications and formats, whether resizing for different media or customising designs for distinct and overseas markets
- A keen eye for detail and a passion for delivering pixel perfect artwork, working in a fast-paced environment
- Collaborating and building positive, lasting relations with account handling teams and key partners when managing a range of projects simultaneously
- > Pre-press experience, mastery of organising files for print and setting up cutter guides and mastery of die-cutting
- High proficiency in industry-standard design software including Figma, Photoshop, Indesign, Illustrator, Acrobat, Sketch and MS Office
- > Knowledge of hand-coding and timeline animated HMTL banners, using HTML, CSS and JavaScript (Greensock); view my animations at hegartyanimations.com
- > Produced social media 2D animations using After Effects; view my motion work on my YouTube channel
- > Independent with good problem-solving skills. Have a proactive approach to identifying and resolving issues which arise in the artworking and production process
- > Strong enthusiasm for keeping abreast of industry trends and new design software/tools

## **CAREER**

# Freelance Senior Integrated Artworker SEAN HEGARTY CREATIVE LTD (May 2023 – date)

> Clients and agencies I've worked for recently include Dyson, Trinny London, Anagram, Socrates Communications, Stanley's Post, Uncommon London and Performance 54

# Senior Design Engineer RAPP (Feb 2021 – Dec 2022)

Worked within the Creative Studio where traditional creative design craft is mixed with cutting edge technology to produce beautiful, personalised work at scale. It was a varied, hybrid role incorporating design, digital artwork, and front-end development disciplines.

> Accounts I worked on while at RAPP included Burberry, Virgin Media, Ralph Lauren, Montblanc, PayPal, Laithwaites, IKEA and Mercedes-Benz

# Freelance Senior Integrated Artworker SEAN HEGARTY CREATIVE LTD (Jun 2013 – Jan 2021)

> Clients and agencies who I've worked with include Identity Design, The Honest Brand, A Place for Rover, Splash Worldwide, Canary Wharf Group, Digitas, NKD Learning, Suburbia, Audio Network Limited, Effection, Me&Dave, Chelsea Football Club, Axa Insurance, Comic Relief, Sectorlight, Wallace Health, Quill Content, Mindshare, Health Circle, Digitas Health Lifebrands, Agora Health, Lambert Smith Hampton, Saatchi Health, Conrad Design Group, Lebara, Architas, Jones Lang LaSalle, Anderson Norton Design, Ampersand, FKA Studios, Lockton Insurance, Adstream, M&G Investments, Savills, Audience Media, The Football Association, G4S, Avery Dennison, Publicis Life Brands, BlackRock, Lusso, Initial, Law Creative and BrocklebankPenn

# Head of Studio GUNGHO DESIGN (Jul 2010 – May 2013)

- > Managing 5 designers and a team of freelancers
- > Focus on designing and artworking bid documents and interactive presentations
- > Communicating a clear vision to the design team
- > Project managing multiple complex projects

## Artworker

**UBS** (GLOBAL ASSET MANAGEMENT) (Aug 2008 – Jul 2010)

- > Produced print-ready artwork for the Business Development Team
- > Created regular financial and corporate reports
- > Worked under pressure to meet a succession of client deadlines

## **TESTIMONIALS**

'Sean was a real pleasure to work with, always showed initiative and created work to the highest standard. We would love to work with him again'

#### **Hannah Bush**

Lead Design Engineer RAPP Agency hannah.bush@rapp.com December 2022

'It was an absolute pleasure to have Sean work as part of our team over the last 18 months. Sean has a can-do attitude and demonstrated a highly considered and thoughtful approach to all tasks undertaken. He is extremely professional, has very strong technical skills and made positive and valuable contributions to each project he worked on. Sean will be a very valuable asset to any company that employs him in the future'

## Manuela Zwingmann Wood

Group Marketing Manager (Brand & Residential) Canary Wharf Group Manuela.zwingmannwood@canarywharf.com September 2019

'Sean worked in-house with our team for over six months and completed various design projects, all to a high standard and in a timely manner. He is extremely hard-working, professional and very detail-oriented – an asset to any company'

#### **Emma Gowdie**

Associate Publisher Agora Health UK September 2016

'Sean is a real pleasure to work with. Focused, selfmotivated, pragmatic and skilled, he can always be trusted to 'just get it done' when you need it. As good alone as he is fitting into a well-established team, Sean is committed and adaptable across media old and new – what's more he's also a really nice guy'

#### **Tom Malt**

Creative Services Director BlackRock August 2015

# **CAREER** (continued)

# Pitch Executive CB RICHARD ELLIS (Aug 2007 – Aug 2008)

- > Provided design support for the in-house Pitch & Proposal Team
- > Prepared presentations for client pitches, such as interactive presentations, brochures, banners and moodboards
- > Project managed and designed large strategic proposal documents

# Design Specialist DEUTSCHE BANK (Feb 2001 – Aug 2007)

- > Designed and formatted bespoke and branded printed documents and on-screen presentations
- Developed an understanding of colour management and the power of using styles, layers, grids, and parent pages

## **EDUCATION**

BA Joint – Honours Degree Leicester University (1989 – 1992)

### **INTERESTS**

Design trends, reading non-fiction, travelling, eating out, NFL, photography, cycling, running, coding, current affairs, exploring London.

07855 456521

hegartycreative.com

hegartyanimations.com

YouTube channel